A Finding Aid to the Hugo Gellert Papers, 1916-1986, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, circa 1920-1986; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, 8
  National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors: 1940 (Bianca Todd)
  National Council of American Soviet Friendship: 1943 (Hannah Dorner)
  National Council of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions: 1952 (Nan Bramer)
  National Maritime Union: 1944 (Louis Oguss, M. Hedley Stone)
  New Masses: 1934 (Sean, Herman Michelson)
  New World Review: 1952 (Jessica Smith)
  New York Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born: 1955 (Alec Jones)
  Nuno, B.: 1943
  Oguss, Louis: 1944
  Oldham, John and Ray: circa 1930s
  Ottley, Roi: 1943 (National CIO Committee)
  Patrás, Pal: 1955
  Patterson, William L.: 1953-1954
  People's World: 1956 (W.J. Decker)
  Perlo, Ellen: 1984
  Perrot, Paul: 1960 (Corning Museum)
  Philadelphia Forum of Social Sciences: 1955 (Bob Klonsky)
  Popper, Lilly: 1953-1954
  Prentis, Albert: 1937
  Provisional Workers and People's Committee for May Day: 1955 (Morris Gainer), 1960 (Max Rosen)
  Putnam and Sons: 1935 (Quintin Rossi)
  Reed, Alman: 1955
  Reisman, Philip: 1962, circa 1960s
  Rickey, George: 1937
  Rosen, Max: 1955
  Rosner, A.: 1952, 1959
  Rosner, Deak: 1955
  Rossen, John: 1955
  Rossi, Quintin: 1935
  Royce, Edward: 1955
  Sandburg, Carl: 1942
  Sapiro, Aaron: 1932
  Schappes Defense Committee: 1941 (Morris U. Shappes)
  Schoen, Eugene: 1932, 1934
  Schwartz, Morris: 1951
  Selsam: 1951
  Sequenzia, Sofia: 1983
  Shields, T.A. "Art": 1959
  Shillen, Ronald: 1942
  Siegelbaum, Portia: 1978
  Sillen, Samuel: 1952
  Smith, Jessica: 1952
  Soglow, Otto: 1942
  Solomon: Dave: 1954 (New Talents Gallery), 1956
  Starobin, Joseph: 1955
  Steffens, Lincoln: 1934 (journalist)
  Stone, M. Hedley: 1944
  Street, Julian Jr.: 1940
  Tandy, W. Lou: 1953
  Time: 192-
  Todd, Bianca: 1940 (See also Series 4)
  Tresca, Carlo: circa 1930s (anarchist)
  Turner, Jeannette S.: 1957-1960
  Tyler, Hugh: 1939 (WPA)
  Vallon, Jose: 1934
  Van Rensselaer, Sylvia: 1944 ("Portrait of America Competition" report)
  Weber, Max: 1953 (See also Series 4)
  Weyhe Gallery: 1947
  Wilson, Steve: 1959 (Progressive Lithographers)
  The Worker: 1952 (Rob Hall)
  World Council of Peace: 1955 (Jean Laffitte)
  World: 1925
  Zigrosser, Carl: 1937
  Zorach, Bill: 1942
  Zundel, Eugenia: 1957, 1959
  Zurier, Rebecca: 1984, circa 1980s
  - Correspondence, circa 1920-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8
  - Correspondence, 1932-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, circa 1930-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, circa 1940-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1950 January-August; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1950 September-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1952 January-September; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1952 September-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1953 February-July; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1953 July-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 1954 January-August; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1954 August-November; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1955 January-March; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, 1955 April-September; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, 1955 September-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957 January-February; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1957 March-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1959 January-July; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1959 July-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, circa 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1960 January-May; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1960 May-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1962; 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, circa 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, circa 1980-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Oversized Item from Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
    Oversized material digitized with Box 1, Folder 25
- Writings, 1916-1970; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Box 2
  This series includes essays, short stories, notes, lists, notebooks, and a play. Most writings are by Hugo Gellert. Articles and stories by other authors, particularly Hungarian are also found.
  Gellert's writings include two full-length typescripts, for Baron Munchausen, His Famous 'Mein Kampf', and Comrade Gulliver, An Illustrated Account of Travel into that Strange Country the United States of America. Other prose writings by Gellert include brief essays on a wide array of historical, political, and biographical topics, as well as writings related to exhibitions. Most of these writings are untitled, but examples of titles that are present include "Siqueiros in Jail," "War," The Role of the Communist Artist," and "Charles White, His Portfolio." Prose writings in the Hungarian language are filed separately.
  Proposals and applications consist mainly of biographical information about Gellert and one page of an application for Robert Gwathmey. Notes include lists of names, agendas, supplies, recipes for art media, and expenses. Some of the notes are in Hungarian, and scattered notes in handwriting other than Gellert's are also found. Sketches are common throughout the notes. Notebooks contain contacts, appointments, writings, sketches, and other records.
  Writings by other authors include articles in English and stories in Hungarian by various authors, filed alphabetically by author. These writings are typically typescripts, and include seven stories by the Hungarian realist writer Zsigmond Móricz. The unsigned typescripts filed at the end of the series may or may not be by Hugo Gellert.
  Additional writings are found in the Organizational Records and Artwork series, including an autobiographical essay in a 1950 sketchbook.
  - Writings by Hugo Gellert, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Baron Munchausen: His Famous Tale 'Mein Kampf', circa 1930-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Comrade Gulliver: An Illustrated Account of Travel into that Strange Country, the USA, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Comrade Gulliver: An Illustrated Account of Travel into that Strange Country, the USA, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Prose Writings in English, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Prose Writings in English, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Prose Writings in English, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Prose Writings in English, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Prose Writings in English, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Prose Writings in Hungarian, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Prose Writings in Hungarian, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Prose Writings in Hungarian, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Prose Writings in Hungarian, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Proposals and Applications, circa 1936-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Lists of Artwork, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Notebook, circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Contains sketches
    - Notebook, circa 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Notebook, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Writings by Others, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Articles, circa 1962; 1970; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Box 2, folders 46-47 include "Jo Davidson" by Van Wyck Brooks, "China Report" by John Chen, an article on the sentence of David Alfaro Siqueiros and Filomeno Mata by Victor Rico Galan, "Second Culture" by Gaylord C. LeRoy, "The Ballad of Gheorghe Doja" by Constantin Palade, and "Facts on New York Labor" by Victor Perlo
    - Articles, circa 1962; 1970; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Stories in Hungarian, 1916; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Authors include Jenö Heltai, Zsigmond Móricz, and István Tömörkény (Box 2, Folders 48-50)
    - Stories in Hungarian, 1916; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Stories in Hungarian, 1916; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Unsigned Typescripts, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Prose Writings in English, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Includes "Chalcography in Hungary," "Political Indifference - Political Death," and untitled essays on the federal art program, artist Robert Minor, and fragments of an essay on the John Reed Club
    - Prose Writings in Hungarian, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Untitled Three-Act Play in English, circa 1930-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Oversized Writings, Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
    Oversized material digitized with Box 2, Folders 27 and 39
- Organizational Records, circa 1920-1977; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 3, 8, and OV 9
  This series contains documents related to political and art organizations for which Gellert was an active organizer, officer, and in some cases, a founder. Because of his central role in many of these organizations, records often contain unique documentation of their activities.
  Typical records found include incoming and outgoing correspondence, membership records, petitions, reports, open letters to public figures in multiple drafts, accounting records, records related to exhibitions, publicity in various forms, meeting agendas and minutes, and Gellert's original notes and writings. Documents are arranged by organization, with records for each organization filed roughly in chronological order. Names of significant correspondents found in this series are listed in a note under the folder heading in which it appears.
  Printed material related to organizations for which no original records are found are filed in the Printed Material series.
  - American Artists Congress, circa 1936-1937; 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Box 3, folders 1-2 include letters of Grace Clements, G. Merangel, Stuart Davis, Thomas Parker
  - American Artists Congress, circa 1936-1937; 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Artists Congress, circa 1937-1937; 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes a 1936 pamphlet of cartoons defending the Works Progress Administration
  - American Artists Congress, Conference Proceedings, First American Artists Congress against War and Fascism, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Box 3, folders 5-14 include letters of Rockwell Kent, Sally Kent, Hilda Simpson, John Kingsbury, Robert Shinn, Clark Foreman, Emil Zinn, and Eleanor Brown
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1955 January-April; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1955 April-July; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Art of Today Gallery, circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1955 August-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1956 January-September; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1956 October-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Art of Today Gallery, circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Art of Today Gallery, circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Art of Today Gallery, Log Books, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Art of Today Gallery, Log Books, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Art of Today Gallery, Amalgamated Bank Book and Receipt Book, 1955-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Artists Committee of Action, circa 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Box 3, folders 18-23 include letters of A. Alfred DeVito, Zoltan Hecht, Josephine Droege, Frederick Detwiller, Samuel Henning, Theo. H. Kleffel, Nathaniel Pousette-Dart, Carla Zimmerman, Madeleine Gray, Leo Mansoni, Victor Frisch, Archie Abraham, Constance Clarke, Lionel S. Reiss, Else Mevis, R.A. Griffith, Edith Bryan, S.A. Sliflein, Basil Marros, Lewis Rubin, Rose Hecht, Irving Bulback, Maurice Rawson, Adam A. Sanders, J.J. Lankes, Ralph Pearson, Max Weber, Joseph Lemarzi, Mrs. Henry Breckinridge, Lillian Cohen, Harry Hoffman, Marion Walton, Frannie Engle, R. Pringle, and Olivia Agee
  - Artists Committee of Action, circa 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Artists Committee of Action, circa 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Artists Committee of Action, circa 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Artists Committee of Action, circa 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Artists Committee of Action, circa 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Box 3, Folders 24-35 include letters of Harold Friedman, George Biddle, George Picken, Marion Bauer, Audrey McMahon, Michael Loew, Henry Lead, E. Nye, Frances M. Pollak, Stuart Davis, Harry Gottlieb, Ruth St. Denis, Ed B. Rowan, Michael Kiss, William C. Palmer, George Horowitz, Maurice Heaton, Paul Bird, Ethel Katz, Fred Knight, J. Scott Williams, Rockwell King, Alfred Barr, Elmer Rice, Nan Golden, Ellen Woodward, Joy Pride, Elizabeth Litchfield, Josephine Droege, Bianca Todd, A. Conger Goodyear, Philip Stein, Algot Stenbery, Arthur Emptage, Letteris Calapari, Ralph Mayer, Ernest Marbury, Corrington Gill, Daniel Cotton Rich, Joseph A. Danysh, Florence Kerr, Howard Lee Irwin, Adrian Dornbush, Hardinge Scholle, and F. Ballard Williams
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, circa 1935-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, circa 1935-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Artists' Council, U.S.A., circa 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Includes letters of Max Weber, José de Creeft, Thomas Hart Benton, and Carol Janeway
  - Artists for Victory, Inc., 1941-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    Box 3, folders 37-41 include letters of Rockwell Kent, Chester Price, John Taylor Arms, Marie Kirkwood, Jim Eglern, Thomas C. Parker, and Erwin Barrie
  - Artists for Victory, Inc., 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Artists for Victory, Inc., 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Artists for Victory, Inc., circa 1941-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Artists for Victory, Inc., circa 1941-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, circa 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    Box 3, folders 42-44 include letters of Joseph North, Philip Evergood, Sara Gottlieb, and Rockwell Kent
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, circa 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, circa 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, Bank Records, 1951-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, Published Writings by Jerome, 1947; 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
    Includes article "Let Us Grasp the Weapon of Culture," and booklet "Culture in a Changing World, a Marxist Approach"
  - Communist Party, circa 1931-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Hungarian Word, Inc., 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Hungarian Word, Inc., 1953-1962; 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Independent Voters Committee of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions (ASP), circa 1944-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - John Reed Clubs, circa 1929-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
    "Proposals for Activities of John Reed Clubs"
  - National Society of Mural Painters (Mural Artists Guild), circa 1936-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - National Society of Mural Painters (Mural Artists Guild), 1937-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - National Society of Mural Painters (Mural Artists Guild), 1939-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - National Society of Mural Painters (Mural Artists Guild), circa 1936-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - New York City Art Commission, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - New York City Council for Art Week, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - United American Artists (formerly the Artists' Union), circa 1930-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Other Organizations' Records, circa 1934-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Oversized Organizational Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
    Oversized material digitized with Box 3, Folders 41 and 50
  - Oversized Organizational Records, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9)
    Oversized material digitized with Box 3, 31
- Printed Materials, circa 1920-1986; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 3 Linear feet Boxes 4-6, 8, and OV 9
  This series contains newspaper clippings, exhibition catalogs, magazines, maps, pamphlets, greeting cards, brochures, mailings, flyers, posters, and books. Printed materials with artwork or writings by Hugo Gellert are filed under his name, as are documents promoting his public appearances and other activities. The remainder of the series is filed by type of material. Although the bulk of the printed materials series has been scanned, some clippings, announcements, invitations, maps, pamphlets, printed short stories, and publicity and mailings were not. Not scanned or partially scanned material is noted at the folder title.
  Gellert's illustrations are found in a wide variety of publications such as books, magazines, pamphlets, flyers, and publicity for various organizations. These materials are arranged by title, type of document, or organization. Serial publications that Gellert helped to produce are filed under the heading "Gellert periodicals." Photocopied clippings contain additional published Gellert illustrations and cartoons.
  Exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations are primarily for exhibitions in which Gellert was not a participant. Pamphlets are mostly political tracts. Multiple pamphlets are filed by publisher, and single instances are filed chronologically under a miscellaneous heading. Multiple periodicals are filed by title, with single instances filed chronologically as well.
  Publicity and mailings received by Gellert are arranged chronologically and include mass mailings such as form letters, flyers, newsletters, bulletins, announcements, circulars, press releases, reports, and other printed materials related to various labor, political, and art organizations. Some of the issues addressed in this material include the Spanish Civil War, advocacy for victims of McCarthyism, May Day demonstrations, civil rights, Soviet-American friendship, Cuba, organized labor, and education. Also found here are scattered programs for cultural events.
  Printed materials related to organizations in which Gellert was a principal organizer are found in the Organizational Records series. Exhibition catalogs for the Art of Today Gallery are also found with Organizational Records.
  - Clippings, circa 1934-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Photocopies of originals dated 1923-1982), circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations, 1929-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8.
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations, 1940-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations, 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)